since the mid-2000s I've been doing a
lot of technical work things like IT
based systems administration Network
administration systems architecture then
I went up to you know director of
technology IT manager that type of thing
and then when I came to China I
continued that same trajectory more
director of technology eventually a CTO
of of a visual effects company here in
China so my background really is in
technical stuff but I resigned
from that career
this year and I finished up writing a
book which is out now and did a couple
of appearances I was on TV and a few
pretty big podcasts and other interviews
and stuff like that so I've kind of
changed my purpose from doing technology
to trying to connect with people out in
the world and communicate about my story
and kind of kind of break out of my
shell
[Music]
now
one of the things that originally drew
me to technology is that no matter how
you look
tattoos or you look you know wearing a
t-shirt actually as long as you can get
the work done efficiently in a good way
better than everyone else as long as you
can kind of be a rockstar at getting
that technological challenge solved
they don't care what you look like no
one cares they don't care and you can
have tattoos on your face and horns if
you can solve their problems then theytheir problems
want you and so that's one of the
reasons that I really started to look at
technology as maybe I can do that
because I had tattoos and I'm I'm not
kind of like a very formal guy and so
technology was what I really started to
look at in the beginning so at the
visual effects company I was working at
here in Beijing I worked there for four
years and it took a while to get used to
the different culture of the work
different work environment and that kind
of thing I didn't have any opportunity
to try to learn John went in school so
all the Chinese that I know is from just
asking people what are you saying what
what is that I'll say it again
what do you mean was that mean how does
that mean so well clay shall eat the NDA
but not too much I was doing technical
management before I came to China and
that continued when I was here but there
was a lot of new challenges like dealing
with the cultural shock dealing with the
cultural differences understanding the
differences in how businesses work and
that kind of stuff I managed around a
hundred people in six cities four in
China one in America and one in Malaysia
it was mostly technical staff but also
heavily interfaced with HR accounting in
the operations teams as a CTO it's an
executive position so mumbles my entire
day is spent with the CEO the CFO the
CEO oh the CCO and the vice-president
and they all have very different job
responsibilities but I'd say that the
CTO is most similar to the CEO Oh
every day I'm out there making sure
stuff is working and people are getting
stuff done and movies are getting made
the way that Western people think about
work leadership and who's in charge of
who and what my responsibilities are and
just all these types of things it's
totally different than the way that
people in China think about them and so
there was a lot of frustration there's a
lot of learning you know and expanding
and growing and being a technical
manager like a director of Technology or
IT manager you can speak the language of
technology to the to your juniors and
they can sort of work with you to get
the best solution going but being an
executive level manager is a bit
different because you interface with a
lot of people who aren't technical and
deal with a lot more interpersonal
skills it was a lot more discovery of
Who I am as a manager and a leader and
there was a lot of mistakes early on a
lot of frustration and not understanding
the cultural differences and how to push
through barriers sometimes I would say
things that the Chinese team would
misunderstand what I meant and think
that I meant something else or they
would say something and I would
misinterpret what they said so these
types of things even with translation
there's a level of interpretation that
that you just kind of need to get a
rhythm for over the years working with
Chinese people I've learned a lot of
things about them a lot of things about
China and I think more importantly a lot
of things about myself you know I've
known a lot of people in my life I've
had many friends and you know I've been
in relationships and all that kind of
stuff and I say that the thing that
really strikes me about Chinese people
that I never knew about them before is
that I feel like Chinese people are very
similar to myself in some ways that are
kind of interesting I feel in some ways
closer to Chinese people than I do my
own people even though I have of course
many good friends many close
relationships in the West no offense to
you guys but in general I tend to get
along with Chinese people a little bit
better I think that we kind of
understand things in a similar way you
know they tend to work together on
things and tend to have certain views
about the world and about their country
and themselves that I just really find
wonderful and
another thing that I think I learned
about Chinese people is that they're
really into teams right they really like
to build stuff as a team build things
together and to cooperate to get things
done which is really nice because in the
West you get a bunch of people who all
try to go and be mr. hero and go try to
save the day and a lot of them just suck
at what they do they just have been told
that they're good they they're told that
they're amazing they're told that
they're special all the time that
they're this amazing person they're not
good at their job and so you have to
like get them all together
careful their fragile ego you know don't
insult them when try they like they're
just like babies I don't know and
there's something different about the
way people work in China where you have
people that are kind of more focused on
getting the job done like actually
working and I have a very strong work
ethic and I you know I just really
appreciate that is something that I
didn't know about Chinese people there's
so many things that I want to say about
Chinese people not just that work but
also my personal relationships with them
some of my close friends here my band
mates and other people that I really
want to do some videos to kind of
explore the interactions and kind of
really expose what I'm talking about
because I think about these things all
the time very in-depth very detailed and
I come up with these opinions based on
evidence and I think that the way that I
feel about Chinese people is
and you know I'd love to do some videos
about that
[Music]