[Music]
hey guys what's up how are you doing
today welcome back to this YouTube
channel chill guy Iger here guys I got
some good news for you today there was
this application for parent sponsorship
in 2019 January 28 I got him I got in
I'm one of those few lucky people who
got him guys seriously why I'm saying
lucky is that they opened the
application process by 10:00 a.m.
Calgary time it's after noon Eastern
Standard Time right now I'm located
close to Calgary that's Calgary downtown
here guys by 10:00 a.m. they opened it
okay so hundreds of thousand of people I
believe more sitting on the website
refresh in a page to see when they can
submit what Government of Canada did is
you have to go to the Government of
Canada website they did not tell you
where the link is going to be they said
they will post it on Facebook so what
they did is by 10:00 exactly they opened
the link and fortunately for me it was
there right away
I went into that link pull up all the
information my name my address you know
my PR card number email address my
birthday and my parents so I had
everything pre-planned I had my work pad
open and I just had my parents names
there so I already wrote down though
their data and birthday so I had to just
copy/paste it literally through the
entire application although I think I'm
pretty I screwed up on one of the things
there I think I put my country of versus
Canada and country of residence is
Canada I don't remember if I put Ukraine
or Canada and I don't know there is no
way to check it
but anyways guys short story is this I
was a little bit delayed because what
had happened is my wife she wanted to
sponsor her parents and I wanted to
sponsor my parents at the same time so
at the same time we were on the phone we
opened the links and she was filling up
application for her parents and I was
pulling up for my parents
cherlene couldn't open ok at the
beginning she couldn't find the link it
wouldn't refresh the page so she was
about like I if you did my application
about three minutes my wife I don't I
don't exactly know how much I'm sure
maybe five minutes or something so what
had happened guys is they like literally
in five minutes or so they have accepted
27,000 applications from people who own
to sponsor their parents to come to
Canada from those people who have been
waiting for years and some of them were
waiting like to solve an 11 you know to
get their parents to come to Canada and
all that like a huge mass of people who
went on the website and in five minutes
27,000 applications were done like the
government says about 10 minutes or so
but I think it was even faster I it took
me about three minutes to finish the
application because I was ready I I knew
what is required on that application I
did it last year I didn't get through so
I did this year unfortunately I think
this current application got submitted I
got my confirmation number but it was a
crazy challenge it was like you cannot
proofread at you and don't have time to
go through the application find out it's
like you know if they made something
where you can preview the application
and just when their time comes you just
hit submit it would be easy but what
they did Government of Canada is they
didn't give you the link so you don't
know where to go on the website where's
the plate you know what to do well lucky
I guess on which page is going to be
where you know apply to sponsor your
parents on the top it was saying you
know it's going to open by afternoon and
everything so yeah that thing
disappeared and then link to sponsor
your parents appear so luckily
just hit there and I was on the right
place guys who I'm saying is it was kind
of a mess when I went to Facebook there
are so many people frustrated about it
you know so many people who didn't go
through and it just amazes me how many
solvents are like maybe ten thousand
hundred thousand I don't know how many
people try to do it but what it did is
you fill out their application and then
you click Submit and it just says sorry
like literally sorry we don't accept
anymore
we are full you know like to wait there
is also a big suspicion that some people
some computer engineers might have
developed a script or something while
there is less opinions because there is
no there is no like a clicky thing on
the bottom you know for a googly cut
capture captain recapture something I
forgot on my website I have it so that I
don't have bought spam in my inbox on
the thing guys for all of you who are
planning to come to Canada you see I'm
going through the same phases as you are
basically guys I'm still going through
immigration even though you know I talk
a little bit a lot and behold Canada and
I'm still they don't still going through
citizenship application my ceremony is
going to be in about two months now I'm
trying to trying working on sponsoring
my parents to Canada still going through
all the stages that you're going guys
it's it's crazy I know what if you are
already in Canada but anyways guys after
you come to Canada there is still a huge
journey you know to get the citizenship
to get your parents here you know to
bring your family and finally enjoy
their you know the beautiful beautiful
Canada guys it's beautiful here you
don't like look at the trees and you
know the downtown and Calgary it's nice
and touch the country and it's always
better to enjoy it with your family all
right I want to thank you so much for
watching guys thank you for subscribing
like this video if you think is helpful
and more importantly share your story
were you there today during that process
did you submit your applications did you
get through what challenges did you face
share your story guys it's really
important to us
let's make Canadian government hear us
because believe me when I say they do
watch our videos they do what it's part
of their job to listen to the community
alright guys we'll see you next video
thank you so much and be sure the best
have a good one
I'm gonna get y'all one now because it's
free kids also finally guys who last
year I don't know it didn't go through
this year hopefully I'll get an
invitation to get my parents sponsor to
Canada guys hopefully I'm like I'm just
like seriously I really I really wanted
I really needed it oh it will be awesome
have a good one guys
gonna eat some shawarma
hey my disbelief and make me forget
No
[Music]
put your bra